Guide to the Montana Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services, Office of Legal Affairs records 1970-1995
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Montana Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services, Office of Legal Affairs records
1970-1995
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
RS 465
Montana. Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services.
12 linear feet of shelf space
The records of the Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services are comprised of correspondence, Administrative Rules Review files, case files, legislative files; and subject files.
Administrative History
The Legislature established the Department of Public Welfare in 1937, consolidating state welfare activities. The Department was responsible for the administration of all forms of public assistance, including general relief programs and supervision of institutions caring for the dependent, delinquent, or mentally or physically handicapped. In 1971 the Department of Public Welfare was abolished and its functions assumed by the newly created Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services (SRS). The SRS assumed the functions of various state agencies, including functions pertaining to vocational rehabilitation and education; the Commission on Aging; and the Council on Human Resources. The SRS administered all forms of public assistance, child protection, and child welfare; gave consultant service to private institutions providing care for the needy, indigent, handicapped, or dependent; developed provisions for services to the blind; supervised county boards of public welfare; and administered all funds allotted for public welfare activities. State government reorganization in 1995 combined the SRS with portions of the Department of Health and Environmental Sciences to form the Department of Public Health and Human Services.
Content Description
The records of the Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services are comprised of correspondence by creator; Administrative Rules Review files relevant to a wide variety of Social and Rehabilitation Services functions; case files regarding licensure and revocations of licenses for eateries, hotels, health care facilities, and residential buildings, as well as cases related to Medicaid reimbursement of medical professionals; legislative files; and subject files regarding individual facilities and businesses, as well as information on SRS divisions and policies.
This collection is arranged by series.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Adult day care centers; Alcoholism; Ambulance service; Children with disabilities; Day care centers; Drug addiction; Food industry and trade--standards; Group homes; Immunization of children; Mental health facilities; Nursing homes; Psychiatric hospitals; Quarantine; Wild animals as pets
Montana
Medicine and Health
Mental Health
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence
  - Eleanor (Ellie) Parker, DHES Counsel, 1994 (Box-folder 1 / 1-2)
  - Dayna Shepherd, 1994 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Cynthia (Cindy) Brooks, 1994 (Box-folder 1 / 4-5)
  - Eleanor (Ellie) Parker, 1993 (Box-folder 1 / 6-7)
  - Eleanor (Ellie) Parker, 1992 (Box-folder 1 / 8-9)
  - Eleanor (Ellie) Parker, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 10-11)
- Administrative Rules Reviews
  - Daycare Use of Child Diapers, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - Handicapped Children’s Services Federal Poverty Guidelines, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - Handicapped Children’s Services Program, 1990 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - Specialized Mental Health Facilities, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 15-18)
  - Fee Increase for Birth, Death, or Fetal Death Certificates, 1991 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - End-Stage Renal Disease, 1991 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - Licensure and Requirements for Laboratory Microbiological Analysis, 1991 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Laboratory and Analyses Fees, Increase of, 1991 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - Certificate of Need: Long-Term Care, 1984 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
  - Certificate of Need: Psychiatric Hospitals, 1983 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - Certificate of Need: Forms, 1983 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
  - Certificate of Need: Health Care Facilities, 1983 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - Certificate of Need: AMD, 1982 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - Chemical Dependency Treatment Centers, 1984 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Personal Care, Adult Day Care, Intermediate Care, 1984 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - Hospice Licensure Standards, 1983 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - MAC – Abortion Rule, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - MAC – Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - MAC – Alcohol Services, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - ARM Ambulance Licensing Regulations, 1972 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - ARM Annual Review, 1976 (Box-folder 2 / 17)
  - MAC Community Homes, Licensing, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 18)
  - MAC Community Homes for the Developmentally Disabled, 1975 (Box-folder 2 / 19)
  - MAC Disinterment Permit Rule, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 20)
  - MAC Disposition, Transit of Dead Bodies, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 21)
  - MAC Food, Consumer Safety, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 22)
  - MAC Food Processing Establishments, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 23)
  - MAC Food Service Establishments, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 24)
  - MAC Group Homes, Halfway Houses, 1976 (Box-folder 2 / 25)
  - MAC Hospital, Constructions – Licensing Rules, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 26)
  - MAC Infant Screening – Inborn Metabolic Errors, 1974 (Box-folder 2 / 27)
  - ARM Records and Statistics Forms, 1977 (Box-folder 2 / 28)
  - MAC School District Immunization, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 29)
  - MAC Vital Statistics Changes, 1973 (Box-folder 2 / 30)
  - ARM Communicable Diseases, 1980 (Box-folder 2 / 31)
  - Immunization Schools, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 2 / 32-35)
  - Measles Quarantine, 1979 (Box-folder 2 / 36)
  - Reportable Diseases, 1980 (Box-folder 2 / 37)
  - Reportable Diseases – Category D, 1981 (Box-folder 2 / 38)
  - School Immunization, 1982 (Box-folder 2 / 39)
  - Schools/Daycare Facilities – TB Test, 1981 (Box-folder 2 / 40)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 22, No date (Box-folder 2 / 41-42)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 28 Communicable Disease Control, 1980 (Box-folder 2 / 43)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 30 Emergency Medical Services, No date (Box-folder 2 / 44)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 32 Healthcare Facilities, 1979 (Box-folder 2 / 45)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 38 Laboratories, No date (Box-folder 2 / 46)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 6 Records and Statistics, 1979 (Box-folder 2 / 47)
  - Recodification Preparation – Chapter 10 Food and Consumer Safety, No date (Box-folder 2 / 48, 3 / 1)
  - Schools Immunization, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Immunization in Schools, 1980 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
  - Tumor Registry, New Rules, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Fees for Copies/Research, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Records and Statistics, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 5-6)
  - Records and Statistics/Abortion Reports, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Vital Statistics Records, Access to, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
  - Ambulance Licenses, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
  - Ambulance Service Licensing, 1977 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
  - Dance Halls and Pleasure Resorts, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - Food Drug and Cosmetic Act, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
  - Food Service Establishments, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 13-14)
  - Hotels, Motels, Rooming houses, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - Meat standards, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - Nuisances, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - Railway Stations and Cars, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
  - Rummage and Second-hand Clothing, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 19)
  - Tourist Campgrounds, 1982 (Box-folder 3 / 20-21)
  - Trailer Courts/Tourist Campgrounds, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 22)
  - Nursing Bureau, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 23)
  - Funds, Distribution to Local Health Services, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 24)
  - Child Nutrition Program – State Plan, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 25)
  - Day Care Centers, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 26)
  - Day Care Centers – Health Care Requirements, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 27)
  - Day Care Centers, Standards for Certification, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 28)
  - Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) State Plan, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 29)
  - Fees for Analysis of Private Household Water Supplies, 1981 (Box-folder 3 / 30)
  - Laboratory Fees/Tests: Air, Microbiological, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 31)
  - Laboratory Fees – Drinking Water, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 32)
  - Premarital Serological Tests, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 33)
  - Health Care Facility Licensing/Consultation, 1980 (Box-folder 3 / 34)
  - Certification of Need, 1979 (Box-folder 3 / 35)
  - Certificate of Needs – Nursing Home Beds, 1977 (Box-folder 3 / 36)
  - Alder Steak House and Trailer Court, 1978 (Box-folder 3 / 37)
  - Delayed Birth Records, 1986 (Box-folder 3 / 38)
  - Death Certificate, Court Order, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 39)
  - Communicable Diseases, AIDS Emergency and Permanent Rules, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 40)
  - Certificate of Need: Review Forms, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 41)
  - Certificate of Need: Review, Emergency Rules, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 42)
  - Certificate of Need: Swing Beds, Long-Term Care, 1985 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
  - Minimum Standards, Hospital Records, 1986 (Box-folder 3 / 43)
  - Tumor Registry, Laboratory Reports, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 44)
  - Premarital Serological Tests, 1983 (Box-folder 3 / 45)
  - Campgrounds, Private, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 46)
  - Food Service Establishments, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 47)
  - Hotels, Motels, Rooming Houses, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 48)
  - Schools, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 49)
  - Work Camps, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 50)
  - Youth Camps, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 51)
  - Laboratory Fees, 1985 (Box-folder 3 / 52)
  - Laboratory Fees: Air, Water, 1984 (Box-folder 3 / 53)
  - Certificate of Need (procedures), 1985 (Box-folder 9 / 3)
  - Certificate of Need, 1982 (Box-folder 9 / 4)
  - Certificate of Need, 1979 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
- Case Files
  - Adams, George (unsanitary conditions, goats at large), 1972 (Box-folder 3 / 54)
  - Andrus Hotel (Dillon), 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 55)
  - Blains Mobile Home Court F and CS, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3 / 56)
  - Calvert Hotel (Lewistown), 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 57)
  - Chester Trading Company (Meat Market), 1974 (Box-folder 3 / 58)
  - Condor Hotel (Anaconda), 1974 (Box-folder 3 / 59)
  - Conrad Hotel (Conrad), 1970-1977 (Box-folder 3 / 60)
  - Fairmont Hot Springs (Gregson), 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 61)
  - F and C.S.B. General, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 3 / 62)
  - Food Purveyor’s License, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 3 / 63)
  - Hagerty Hotel (Browning), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 3 / 64)
  - Harris Apartments (Great Falls), 1973 (Box-folder 3 / 65)
  - Hotel Matters, 1972 (Box-folder 3 / 66)
  - Johnny’s House of Fine Foods, 1976 (Box-folder 3 / 67)
  - LaSalle Hotel (Butte), 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 68)
  - Licensing - Food and Consumer Safety Bureau, 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 69-70)
  - Licensing – Food and Consumer Safety – Seasonal Operators, 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 71)
  - Licensing – Food Service Establishments, 1978 (Box-folder 3 / 72)
  - Licensing – Hotels, Motels, 1978 (Box-folder 3 / 73)
  - Licensing – Trailer Courts, Campgrounds, 1978 (Box-folder 3 / 74)
  - Lockwood School District No. 26 Declaratory Ruling, 1978 (Box-folder 3 / 75)
  - Masher, Inc. Merlin Fjarli, owner, 1976 (Box-folder 3 / 76)
  - Meat Processing Plants, 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Montana Mosquito Control Association (FCSB), 1978 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
  - Mosquito Control Districts, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
  - New Elk Café and Bar, 1972 (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - 1001 Outlet Store F and CS Bureau, 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - Palace Rooms (Havre), 1974 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Perry’s Rooms (Chinook), 1975 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - Rescue Mission (Great Falls), 1975 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
  - Rogers Motor Inn (Malta), 1972 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
  - Roosevelt Hotel (Glasgow), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
  - Sanders County Jail, No date (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Siderius, Henry, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
  - Rainbow Hotel (Great Falls), 1972-1975 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - Range Riders Ledge (Silver Gate), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 4 / 14)
  - United Campground, West Yellowstone F and CS, 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 15)
  - VFW Rimrock Post 8952 Sunburst, MT, 1976 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
  - Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) State Plans, 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
  - Child Nutrition Program State Plans, 1980 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - Trauma System, 1995 (Box-folder 4 / 19-20)
  - Tribal Contracts, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 4 / 21-24)
  - Independent Home Health/Westmont (Jefferson County), 1986 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
  - Linder vs. Missoula County vs. State of Montana – Liability for Failure to Inform Potentially Exposed Persons to tuberculosis (RESTRICTED), 1990 (Box-folder 4 / 25-28)
  - Clark Fork Valley Hospital (Swing Beds), 1986 (Box-folder 4 / 29)
  - Con-Legal Reviews, 1990 (Box-folder 4 / 30)
  - Thunderchild Treatment Center, Crow Agency, Indian Jurisdiction Issue, 1989 (Box-folder 4 / 31)
  - Great Falls Day Care Association Misuse of Funds, 1989 (Box-folder 4 / 32)
  - Hardin vs. Missoula County vs. DHES (Tuberculosis) (RESTRICTED), 1986 (Box-folder 4 / 33-34)
  - END
  - Hardin v. Missoula County v. DHES Part II [RESTRICTED] (Box-folder 9 / 7)
  - St. Vincent (Cardiac Surgery) Reconsideration Hearing Part III Exhibits, 1988 (Box-folder 5 / 1-5)
  - St. Vincent (Cardiac Surgery) Reconsideration Hearing Part IV Deaconess Brief, Testimony, Transcript, 1988 (Box-folder 5 / 6-9)
  - Missoula Nursing Home Batch Transcripts, 1987 (Box-folder 5 / 10-13)
  - Missoula Nursing Home Batch – Applications, Exhibits, Pre and Post-Hearing Documents, 1987 (Box-folder 5 / 14 – 6 / 7)
  - ENDS AFTER 5 / 12
  - Broadwater Hospital – Townsend, MT, 1980 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
  - Cat Scannes, 1980 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
  - Legal Review, 1989 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Correspondence Melby, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 11)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Research, Mandamus, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Opinions, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Scratch Notes of K. Orr, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 14)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Melby Settlement Offers, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – [label lost], 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 16)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Rimrock, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 17)
  - Rimrock Foundation vs. DHES – Mandamus, 1990 (Box-folder 6 / 18)
  - Immanuel Lutheran Home, Kalispell (reconsideration hearing part I), 1988 (Box-folder 6 / 19-20)
  - Immanuel Lutheran Home (answer to requests for admissions, part II), 1988 (Box-folder 6 / 21-22)
  - Trailer Courts and Campgrounds, 1972 (Box-folder 9 / 8)
  - General, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 9 / 9)
  - Hughes v. Coomber, Mandamus, Death Certificate, 1980 (Box-folder 9 / 10)
  - Congregate Family Style Homes (Mike Hamilton and Dianne Ryker), 1988 (Box-folder 9 / 11)
  - Plains Ambulance Service, 1984 (Box-folder 9 / 12 – 10 / 1)
  - Helena Nursing Home, 1985 (Box-folder 10 / 2-7)
  - Helena Nursing Home (partial transcript), 1985 (Box-folder 10 / 8)
  - Helena Nursing Home (reconsideration hearing), 1986 (Box-folder 10 / 9-14)
  - Shodair/Great Falls Deaconess hearing (application for certificate of need to establish a chemical dependency unit in Billings, MT by Deaconess Medical Center of Great Falls and Shodair Children’s Hospital of Helena), 1986 (Box-folder 10 / 15-18, 11 / 1-2)
  - Shodair/Great Falls Deaconess hearing (application for certificate of need to establish a chemical dependency unit in Billings, MT by Deaconess Medical Center of Great Falls and Shodair Children’s Hospital of Helena), 1986 (Box-folder 6 / 23-27)
  - Shodair/Great Falls Deaconess hearing (application for certificate of need to establish a chemical dependency unit in Billings, MT by Deaconess Medical Center of Great Falls and Shodair Children’s Hospital of Helena), 1986 (Box-folder 6 / 8 – 7 / 7)
  - West-Mont Community Care, Inc. v. Board of Health and Environmental Sciences; Department of Health and Environmental Sciences; Jean K. Comac and Marjorie M. Anderson, d/b/a Independent Home Health Care, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 11 / 3-14)
  - Valley Nursing Home v. Board of Health and Environmental Sciences and Parkview Convalescent Center, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 11 / 15-25)
  - Montana Health Systems Agency, Inc. and Montana Nursing Home Association v. Montana Board of Health and Missoula General Hospital, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 11 / 26 – 12 / 1)
  - Alcohol Facilities (rules), n.d. (Box-folder 12 / 2)
  - Wheel Estates, 1983 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
  - ACLU v. DHES, 1982 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
  - Stewart et al. v. Region II, Child and Family Services, 1989 (Box-folder 13 / 1-3)
  - Fair hearing of Thelmer Berland, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 13 / 4)
  - Fair hearing of Steven Wagner, 1983 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
  - Wagner et al. v. SRS (deposition of Thomas Fritch), 1984 (Box-folder 13 / 6)
  - Wagner et al. v. SRS (Discovery/provider response), 1984 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
  - Wagner et al. v. SRS (Discover/state response), 1984 (Box-folder 13 / 8)
  - Wagner et al. v. SRS (exhibits), 1984 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
  - Wagner et al. v. SRS (F.H.P. #84-582), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 14 / 2-5)
  - Wagner v. SRS (no. 88-318), 1987-1990 (Box-folder 14 / 6-9)
  - Stephen Wagner v. SRS (discovery) [RESTRICTED], 1987-1990 (Box-folder 14 / 10-11)
- Legislative Files
  - Wild Pets, Restricting Possession of 1991 Session (Box-folder 7 / 8)
  - Miscellaneous Bills of Interest, Records and Statistics, 1991 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
  - Emergency Medical Services Bill drafts, 1987 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
  - Clean Indoor Air Act, 1987 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
  - Miscellaneous Bills of Interest to FO, 1987 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
  - Statutory Appropriation – Local Board Inspection Fund, 1986 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
  - Certification of Need, 1986 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
  - Health Information Center Deletion, 1986 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
  - Miscellaneous Bills of Intent to Licensing and Certification, 1987 (Box-folder 7 / 15)
  - General, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
  - Adulterated/Misbranded Articles, Detainer of, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 16)
  - Foreign Meat Labeling, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
  - Hamburger Standards/Menu Labeling, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 18)
  - Jails, Rulemaking Authority, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 19)
  - License Fee Monies Earmarked, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 20)
  - Trailer Court/Definition, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 21)
  - Environmental Chemistry Laboratories/Licensure, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 22)
  - Marriage Certificate (Examination Requirement), 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 23)
  - Rabies, Wild Animal Possession, Prohibition, 1980 (Box-folder 7 / 24)
  - Certificate of Need, 1980 (Box-folder 12 / 7-8)
  - Certificate of Need (samples, other state laws), 1981 (Box-folder 12 / 9)
  - Tumor Registry, 1980 (Box-folder 12 / 10)
  - Vital Statistics, Certificates, Family, 1980 (Box-folder 12 / 11)
- Subject Files
  - Alcohol and Drug Dependence, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7 / 25-26)
  - Ambulance Service – Variance Hoeruer-Waldorf, 1972 (Box-folder 7 / 27)
  - Anaconda Company Ambulance Service, 1977 (Box-folder 7 / 28)
  - Appeal – Re-construction of a Long-Term Care Facility, Livingston, 1973 (Box-folder 7 / 29)
  - B and T Management, 1974 (Box-folder 7 / 30)
  - Blackfeet Nursing Home (license revocation), 1977 (Box-folder 7 / 31)
  - Boehm, Edward 122 Review, 1975 (Box-folder 7 / 32)
  - Building Code Council, 1973 (Box-folder 7 / 33)
  - Centralized Services, 1975 (Box-folder 7 / 34)
  - Clark Fork Valley Hospital, 1978 (Box-folder 12 / 12)
  - Columbus and Deaconess Hospitals (Great Falls), 1975 (Box-folder 7 / 35)
  - Flor-Haven Rest Home, 1972 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
  - Friendship Villa, 1977 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
  - Glasgow AFB, 1974 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
  - Grace Rest Home, 1974 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
  - Public Health Services, County, City-County, “district” Public Health Departments, 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
  - Halfway House, 1972 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
  - Hauck, Herman, 1974 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
  - Health Planning and Resource Division, 1976 (Box-folder 12 / 13)
  - Helfrich, Richards (Human Rights Commission), 1978 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
  - Hobson Volunteer Fire Department and Ambulance Service, 1976 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
  - Hospitals - Information, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
  - Hospital-Medical Facilities, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 8 / 11-12)
  - Koski, Charles H., 1975 (Box-folder 8 / 13)
  - Laboratory, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 8 / 14-19)
  - Maternal and Child Health Services, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 8 / 20-21)
  - Mineral County vs. Department of Health and Environmental Sciences, 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 22)
  - Missoula General Hospital, 1975 (Box-folder 8 / 23)
  - Mountain View Rest Haven, 1980 (Box-folder 8 / 24)
  - Outpatient Surgical Centers, 1974 (Box-folder 8 / 25)
  - Park Place Nursing Home (Great Falls), 1978 (Box-folder 8 / 26)
  - Park Place Nursing Home Wrongful Death Action (Great Falls), 1980 (Box-folder 8 / 27)
  - Parkside Manor, Helena Hospital and Medical Facilities, 1978 (Box-folder 8 / 28)
  - Records and Statistics, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 8 / 29-34)
  - SRS Petitions for Access to Vital Statistics, 1976 (Box-folder 8 / 35)
  - Royal Manor Rest Home, 1976 (Box-folder 8 / 36)
  - St. James Community Hospital (lawsuit), 1975 (Box-folder 8 / 37)
  - Sanders County Memorial Hospital, 1974 (Box-folder 8 / 38)
  - Sangrey, Minnie vs. Director of Department of Health, 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 39)
  - Revocation of License: Silver Bow Annex, 1972 (Box-folder 8 / 40)
  - Uncompensated (medical) services “Free Care”, 1972 (Box-folder 8 / 41)
  - Valle Vista Manor – Lewistown, 1976 (Box-folder 8 / 42)
  - Wibaux Nursing Home, 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 43)